May I help you?
Hey. Wait a minute.
Excuse me. I said,
may I help you?
This is Congressman
Pete McGinnis.
Now...
Mr. Gerard.
No.
Not "Gerard."
Gentry. Craig Gentry.
What are you d...?
I know for a fact
your name is Gerard.
Son of Sam Gerard,
one of the biggest crime
lords on the Eastern Seaboard.
Get out of here.
I'm Pete McGinnis,
U.S. congressman.
And this is a subpoena.
You are hereby summoned
to appear at the
hearing I'm conducting
to investigate the
infiltration of organized crime
within the Atlanta
business community.
I said, get out of here!
You touch him, it's
assault and battery.
I'll see you at the
hearing, Mr. Gerard.
This is very awkward.
The congressman is right.
Sam Gerard is my father.
But I haven't seen or
spoken to him in ten years,
and I don't approve of what
he does any more than you do.
It's why I changed my name,
and it's why I'm on my own.
I'm sorry to put you
through this, but I...
This project is very important.
Not just to me, but
to a lot of people.
And I just hope that
what happened here today
won't adversely
affect your decision
to go forward with
this development.
I'm afraid we're going
to need a little more time
to consider your proposal.
Am I correct?
Gentlemen, I will go
and see the congressman.
I will give him my
full cooperation.
And I will ask that my
name, this company
and this development
be kept out of it.
Well, we need more
time to think about it.
Sam Gerard?
The one and only.
That's big-time underworld.
Your father?
I'm talking big-time underworld.
How come you never told me?
I never told anybody.
All through your divorce
trial, you never told me.
Ten years ago, I made
a deal with my father.
I don't ask him for anything,
and he doesn't
ask me for anything.
Hell, I never even told Diane.
You never told your wife?
No.
I'm sorry I didn't
level with you.
It's just that as far
as I'm concerned,
Sam Gerard isn't my father.
Oh.
I guess I get the picture.
Well, we'd better go talk
with that congressman.
Uh, I'm looking for
Congressman McGinnis.
McGINNIS: In here.
Oh. Okay.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, congressman. Ben Matlock.
We spoke on the phone.
Mr. Matlock. Oh, yeah.
Um... Um, my client and I
are not clear just what it is
you're working on, congressman.
Mr. Matlock...
we believe that syndicate
money has been finding its way
into legitimate
businesses down here.
And the congressional
committee that I chair
finds that very disturbing.
So I've been checking into it.
And guess what?
According to background
checks of the key personnel
of some of the
businesses around here,
it's no rumor.
Well, what does that
have to do with my client?
He's a legitimate businessman.
That may be.
But he doesn't exactly do
business under his birth name,
does he? We're just
checking, that's all.
A... A... A man changes
his name. I don't see...
Okay, okay. So, Sam Gerard...
So, Sam Gerard's my father.
But the reason I changed my
name is because I am sick and tired
of being persecuted
by wimps like you...
Oh, wait a minute.
He didn't mean that.
Uh, congressman...
my client has done
all in his power
to divorce himself
from his family
and its reprehensible
activities.
He himself is very legitimate.
He has nothing to hide.
Then what better way to prove it
than by showing
up at that hearing?
Mr. Gentry is prepared
to cooperate with you fully.
He asks only in return
that you not make his appearance
and testimony public.
Part of our purpose here
is to send a message.
The more we make
public, the better.
Uh, my client is involved in
some very sensitive negotiations
concerning a major
housing development,
which could mean that
thousands of families...
Pete, you made the news.
Channel 7.
No deals, Mr. Matlock. Sorry.
Congressman Pete McGinnis,
armed with a subpoena, went
into this office building today
and confronted Craig Gentry.
Eye News Seven was there,
and here's what happened.
McGINNIS: You are
hereby summoned
to appear at the
hearing I'm conducting
to investigate the infiltration
of Atlanta's business community
by organized crime.
I said, get out of here!
Damn you! Hey. Hold it!
Damn you! Oh, hey. Hey, hold it!
Hey, now! I'm
gonna get you for this.
He's threatening me, counselor.
I'm gonna get you. I swear!
Come on.
I'm sorry.
You want to just go somewhere
and cool off, call me tomorrow?
Pete? Yeah?
I'm, uh, going home.
Do you need anything else?
No. Thanks, Ken.
You have a good one.
Okay. You too. Good night.
Good night.
Pete?
Oh, come on. Don't tell
me you're already here.
That's right, Gary.
We're coming to you live
from the office building at
15589 Peachtree Avenue.
We're investigating
an unconfirmed report
that Congressman Pete
McGinnis has been involved
in some kind of
assassination attempt,
or maybe even worse.
The police are arriving now.
Maybe they can tell us more.
Officer?
Sir, any idea what's
happened up there?
What was he doing
in the building?
He must've been working late.
He always worked late.
He was the hardest
worker I've ever seen.
Morning, lieutenant.
Morning.
Is this building
locked at night?
Yes.
The night watchman
is the only one
who can let you in after 8:30.
That's when he locks up.
And when's the door unlocked?
Seven in the morning.
Then whoever did this
either checked out
with the night watchman
or left this morning.
Or they're still
in the building.
I think you should search
the whole place right now
and talk to everyone.
Someone might've
seen the killer.
Yes, sir.
Morning. Morning.
Lieutenant.
There's a file missing.
Craig Gentry's.
So where'd you go
after you left the congressman?
I, uh... I just got in
my car and I drove.
I finally ended up at a bar.
Had several nice, stiff drinks.
Hm.
When was that?
It was around 9:15, 9:30.
The congressman was
killed between 8 and 10,
and you're 9:15, 9:30.
That puts you at the
bar right in the middle.
Talk to anybody there?
Uh, the... The place
was practically deserted.
I... I talked to the bartender.
I'm a regular, and we've
gotten to be friends.
Well, that's good.
That's good. That
might be a help.
Friends. That's good.
What's his name?
Michael Patrick Xavier Morrison.
Most people call me Mickey.
Occupation?
Bartender at the
Blue Moose Lounge.
You know a Craig Gentry? Yeah.
He's a regular customer.
Did he come in last night?
No. Not last night.
You sure?
Hey, if he'd have been
there, I'd have seen him.
Now, what time did you
leave the Blue Moose?
Eleven-thirty, I guess.
Hm.
Where'd you go then?
I just went home.
I got undressed. I
did a little reading.
And I went to sleep.
You didn't go anywhere else?
Just for a drive to
the bar and home?
Yeah.
That's right. I saw him go
into 15589 Peachtree Avenue.
What time was that, Mr. Silvers?
Eight-twenty, 8:25.
You think you'd recognize
him if you saw him again?
I got mugged by a fare once,
and they never caught the guy.
After that, I've
always made it a point
of giving people
a real good look.
I never forget a face.
Is he in there?
Bingo.
That's the guy.
So it... It was, uh...
All right, Mr. Gerard.
Come with us.
Uh, excuse me. I'm Ben
Matlock, Mr. Gentry's lawyer.
Where are you taking him?
We're booking him
for first-degree murder.
What's your evidence?
About two hours ago,
we got a warrant
to search his home.
We found a bloodstained
knife in the trashcan.
We just got the lab report.
It's the murder weapon.
And we have a witness
that can place him
at the scene of the crime
at the time of the murder.
Come on.
I guess just one stab right
through the heart, huh?
Yeah. Hm.
So when does the coroner
put the time of death?
How's that?
When does the coroner
put the time of death?
Oh.
Uh, sometime,
uh, between 8:35...
That's when one of the
congressman's coworkers
last saw him alive.
And, I believe, it was 10.
Hm.
Well, do you think I should
go find the night watchman?
Hm? The night watchman.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Now, the thing is,
if we can get over
and find this guy.
Um, you go back to the station,
take care of this
thing right here.
I'll have the lab
report around 4 p.m.
All right.
Uh, hi.
Uh, nice to see you again.
I'm sorry. I... I
didn't get your name.
It's Webber. Lieutenant
Webber. Uh, Ben Matlock.
Uh-huh. Uh, are...?
Are you new to Homicide?
I was the liaison
between the department
and the congressman's
investigation.
I know the ins and
outs of his operation,
so I guess it just
made sense to...
To reassign me temporarily.
Oh. Yeah.
Uh, a-a-about the... The
ins and outs of the case, uh...
Excuse me. Uh, Ken? Want to...?
This is Ben Matlock.
This is Ken Long.
Ken was the congressman's
right-hand man.
How do you do? Uh-huh.
I have something
to take care of.
Yeah.
Uh... as he said,
I'm... I'm Ben Matlock.
I'm, uh, Craig Gentry's lawyer.
Yes, I know.
Yeah.
Uh, so...
all these, uh...
These files, you...
Surely you're investigating
people other than my client.
Yes, a lot of people.
But my client was the only one
who came in here
and made threats.
Yes, you could say that.
Yeah.
Uh... well, uh...
Uh, Carl Benedict.
He's supposed to be
pretty big in organized crime.
Yeah, we were looking
at him pretty closely.
And the Martinez family too.
From South America.
Drugs, very violent.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Three-quarters of what
you see around here
has to do with
those two families,
but none of their
files were stolen.
Just your client's.
Let me ask you something.
Doesn't it seem odd...
that my client
would come in here,
kill the congressman and
only take just his own file?
Doesn't that seem
kind of stupid?
Yeah. Pretty dumb.
Well, yeah.
Maybe it should
tell you something.
What time was it when you
locked the front door last night?
At 8:30.
Just like always.
So then what happens
when someone
wants to get into the building
after you've locked the door?
I have to let
everyone in or out.
Even the people who
work in the building?
Nobody has a key to
that door except me.
And it's on my
person at all times.
And you didn't let anybody
in or out the whole night?
No, I didn't. Okay.
Um, what time did you
open the door this morning?
At 6:50, I let in Kenneth Long.
He's... He's the one
who found the body.
And then when the
police showed up,
I unlocked the door
again and left it open.
And there's no other way someone
could've come in or
out of the building?
Not without
setting off an alarm.
Well, maybe the killer
spent the night in the building
and then slipped out after you
opened the door for the police.
Huh.
I appreciate you letting
me come in early like this.
Yeah, well, you won't
mind if I continue working.
I gotta open up
in a half an hour.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
You go right ahead.
So... So that's, uh... That's
pretty much where you were
that night of the murder.
Behind the bar working?
Yeah. That's right.
So, what'd you have? A
pretty good crowd that night?
No. It was real slow.
When Craig Gentry comes
in, where does he usually sit?
Well, just about
where you're sitting.
But you didn't
see him that night.
No.
I didn't see him
because he wasn't here.
Well, he swears he was.
Yeah? Well, he's lying.
Oh.
You know... something...
Something doesn't make sense.
Uh, a man's gonna kill somebody.
Uh, like Craig is supposed to
have killed this congressman.
And he comes up with an
alibi that won't hold water.
And he knows that
it won't hold water
before he comes up with it.
Like, Craig said he was
at the bar here with you,
and if he wasn't,
then he has to know
that you know that.
Does that make any sense?
Ask your client.
Well, maybe I'll ask him.
Hey, fella!
Mr. Morrison?
Hey, Mick!
Hey!
Uh... Uh, I'm Ben Matlock.
We know.
Down!
Come on.
Come on, guys.
Let's go. Come on.
Hut one! Hut two!
Hey.
Come on. Huddle up, huddle up.
There you go. Come on. Come on.
Let's go! Hey!
Down.
Set. Hut one, hut two.
Oh!
Nice, boss. All right. Hey.
Mr. Matlock. MATLOCK: Yes, sir.
Carl Benedict. Oh.
That was a nice catch.
Thank you.
Why haven't we met
before, Mr. Matlock?
I don't know.
I hear you're in court
almost as much as I am.
I, uh...
I was just, uh,
looking at your cars.
Uh, anybody, uh,
drive a blue sedan?
No.
Are you here to talk about
cars or Congressman McGinnis?
Oh. Yeah.
Uh, I understand he was, uh...
He was scrutinizing
your activities.
Yes, of course.
Did you, uh...? That bother you?
I'm always under scrutiny.
Paul.
Where was I on the night
Congressman
McGinnis was murdered?
You were here,
sir. The whole night.
Would you like to step inside?
Yeah.
Set. Hut one, hut two.
Oh, thanks.
Mm.
So, uh...
how you getting along
with Sam Gerard?
He has his
business, I have mine.
How can I best put this?
Um... Yeah, if...
If, uh, Congressman
McGinnis' investigation
was getting to you...
What better way to put an
end to it than to just kill him
and frame the son
of my worst enemy?
No. Ah.
If Sam Gerard ever got
that idea into his head,
it would mean serious
problems for a lot of people.
Yeah. I guess so.
Some people say
that you're working
for the Gerard family now.
Oh, no. That's not true.
I work for Craig Gentry.
Let me presume to give
you a piece of advice.
This is a potentially
explosive situation.
Treat it very carefully.
For all of our sakes.
Including yours.
Oh?
Oh, hm. Hm.
I'll, um... uh, see myself out.
That'll be fine.
How long am I
supposed to stay here?
Just until things calm down.
Thank you.
Tyler.
Yeah?
How long have you
been a private eye?
Well, I've been working for
Ben Matlock a couple years now.
Why?
Because that man's
got the drop on you.
Outside.
You follow... you're dead.
Tyler.
I'd like you to meet someone.
Tyler Hudson,
this is Sam Gerard.
How do you do?
You tell me.
Mr. Matlock?
Yeah? Over here, please.
This car will take you
directly to the penthouse.
Oh?
Hands against the wall, please.
Say what? It's just a formality.
Put your hands
against the wall, please.
Hm.
Should I f...? Should
I feel honored?
Or is this the treatment
everybody gets?
No exceptions, sir.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Uh, this way, please.
Mr. Matlock. I'm
an admirer of yours.
Elliot Atkins. I'm
Mr. Gerard's in-house counsel.
Oh.
I'll be coming over
to your office later on
with all the information we have
on the Benedict and
Martinez business. Hm.
Where's Tyler Hudson?
He's around somewhere.
Would you like a drink?
I want to see him.
You're concerned
that he's not okay?
I assure you he's fine.
After he called you, he
and a couple of our men
ordered some lunch.
Well, where is Sam Gerard?
Mr. Gerard is in
conference at the moment.
Craig. I'm not through.
Craig!
Can you understand?
I want you out. I want
you out of that courtroom.
I want you out of Atlanta.
I want you out of my life.
I'm doing this for you.
This isn't about me.
This is about your pride.
This is about your family name.
This is about your honor.
This is between you and Carl
Benedict, and nobody else.
Least of all me.
But you're a Gerard.
Nobody does this to a
member of my family.
Oh, so, what are you gonna do?
Start a good old-fashioned war?
Kill a couple of dozen
people? Not for me, please.
Once more, I am not a Gerard.
I am not a member
of your family.
Just go home.
Mr. Matlock.
Hello, Mr. Gerard.
How's his defense coming?
Well, we've only just started.
Have you found out who planted
the murder weapon in his house?
No, not yet.
Do you know who
told the cab driver to lie
about seeing him
enter that building?
Or the bartender about
not seeing him in his bar?
No. Uh, we're looking into that.
It's the Benedicts, Mr. Matlock.
They're the ones who
framed my son: the Benedicts.
Well, do you have proof of that?
I'll leave that to you.
I'll stay out of this and give
the legal system a chance.
But if you fail... it's my turn.
I'd like to say a
couple of things.
Of course.
Uh, I, of course,
know who you are.
And I work for, um...
I'll go ahead and
say it: your son.
And if you really
want to help your son...
you'll go back to New York.
I'm not going anywhere
until this matter is settled.
I really hope you
won't do anything
to prejudice this jury.
And one other thing:
I'm gonna overlook
that little stunt
your men pulled
with my friend today.
But if you do anything
like that again,
I will file charges
for kidnapping.
Now, have someone
take me to Tyler Hudson.
Mr. Matlock.
Good luck.
All right.
Full house.
Read 'em and weep there,
gentlemen. Three ace...
Three aces.
A pair of tens. I
hate to win and run,
but my employer calls.
You know what, guys?
Next time, I'm gonna
teach you a game
where only one-eyed
jacks are wild.
They're placing the body
of Congressman McGinnis
into the coroner's wagon now.
Again, he died of some
kind of chest wound.
There's no official word yet
as to how that
wound was inflicted.
Apparently, no weapon
was found at the scene.
Hi, there.
Hi.
Ahem. Ben said you
might need a little help.
Well, I was hoping that somebody
inadvertently got a shot
of the killer sneaking out
of the building that morning
amid all the chaos. Mm-hm.
That's all we have to
report at the moment.
To repeat... At the
moment. To repeat,
we have a definite
confirmation... Hm.
What do you see?
- That's all we have to report...
- That limo driver
was in an awful hurry
to get out of there
once he realized
he was on camera.
- At the moment.
- I can see why.
You recognize him?
That is Rene Morales.
One very bad dude.
He works for the
Martinez outfit.
What outfit is that?
Well, they are the kind of
people that will slaughter ten
to get back at two.
Somebody's gonna have
to go ask this Morales guy
what he was doing outside
the building that morning.
We have a definite confirmation
that United States Congressman
Pete McGinnis is dead.
Oh, you learn so fast.
We'll be following this
story throughout the day.
Back to you, Gary.
Excuse me.
Bartender, tequila and lime.
Ah, what the hell.
Shots all around!
Hey! I mean, how many times
do we get to celebrate
an occasion like this, huh?
Huh? He says...
occasion like what?
Rene Morales' birthday! Yeah!
He says it's not his birthday.
Is that a fact?
Sí.
He says "yes."
Well, I am glad to hear that,
because this is the
sixth bar that I've been to,
and it's the first one that
really knows who he is.
So why don't you tell
him to come on over here,
because old Tyler Hudson
is prepared to buy him a drink.
Or something.
Oh.
And what do you want with Rene?
Um... I just want
to talk with him.
"Tyler Hudson,
Private Investigator."
Are you aware your
driver's license has expired?
You're kidding.
Two months ago.
Damn.
Whatever questions you have
for Rene Morales, you can ask me.
Well, who are you?
Juanita Martinez.
You run the Martinez... Gang?
There is no such thing as a
Martinez gang, Mr. Hudson.
But as an attorney,
I am looked upon by many
as a leader in my community.
And at this moment, I certainly
speak for Rene Morales.
So tell me what the hell
you want, and tell me quickly.
All right, I work
for Ben Matlock,
who is representing
Craig Gentry.
Rene Morales was seen
parked outside of
Congressman McGinnis' office
the morning after the murder.
I was just wondering...
If he had anything
to do with the murder?
Well, he didn't.
He was there because I
had him drive me there.
Oh.
Well, you were in the limo.
Congressman McGinnis
subpoenaed me to testify at his hearing.
I went there to reason with him.
Uh-huh.
That is all I care to discuss.
You are free to go.
Oh, that sounds
like a good plan.
Oh, thank you. Ah.
You owe $25 for the
drinks you bought.
Uh. Wish Rene Morales
a happy birthday for me.
Whenever he has one.
There you are.
Everything you've
always wanted to know
about the Benedicts,
but were afraid to ask.
Let's get one thing
straight right here and now:
It's Elliot.
Elliot Charles Atkins. Mm.
Magna cum laude,
Colgate University.
Columbia Law School. Law review.
Graduated top ten of your class.
Straight from law school
to one of the largest
firms in New York.
You've done your homework.
So have you.
Do the Benedicts know
this much about you?
Not if I have anything
to say about it.
Tell me, Elliot...
why give up the law to
work for the Gerards?
I got to Colgate...
even though my
family was very poor
because I worked
eight hours a day
and carried a full class load.
I got a scholarship
to law school
because I worked hard for it.
And I quit that big law firm
because I didn't want to
become an indentured servant
to some legal corporation.
These were the
only two alternatives?
I grew up with the Gerards.
So...
Craig Gentry is like
a brother to you, huh?
Actually, uh, I hardly knew him.
If a war broke out between
the Gerards and the Benedicts
and the Gerards won,
you'd have a whole new
territory, wouldn't you?
The Gerard family would, yes.
And you're the heir apparent.
You are flirting
with the idea...
that I framed Craig Gentry
in order to start a war.
It's more than a flirtation.
It's a real
possibility, isn't it?
Come on.
Where to?
I'm gonna buy you a drink.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'll have a club soda and...
Uh, two club sodas with lime.
Coming up.
Now...
you think the people I
work for, the Gerards...
You think they're nothing
but a bunch of gangsters, right?
Right.
Nothing could be
further from the truth.
Businessmen.
Very rich, very successful,
very powerful businessmen.
Take Sam Gerard.
His son is being
framed for murder.
He knows it.
He's very upset about it.
Now, in the old days,
there'd be at least three bodies
swinging from meat hooks.
But today, Sam's calm.
Why?
Again, all he wants is
to be a businessman.
For instance, Craig Gentry
was in this very bar
at the time of the murder.
This man here knows that.
Yet he told the police
Craig wasn't here.
Someone paid him to lie?
Mm-hm. Craig knows it.
I know it.
Sam knows it.
Yet he's still breathing. Hm?
Nobody's tied him up,
shot a bullet through
him, have they?
No, of course not.
These are the '80s.
As a matter of fact, do you
have a subpoena on you?
Yeah.
Sign it and let me have it.
Have much do I owe you?
Uh... 4 bucks.
That's fine.
And this is a subpoena.
I'll see you in court.
Now, in the old days,
he would've been tossed
into the Chattahoochee
with a pair of cement overshoes.
Today, that's the last thing
Sam Gerard wants to do.
It's business.
Could I, um, speak with you?
Now? Just for a moment?
It's a nice day
for it, isn't it?
He's my son.
I have a right to be here.
That's correct.
But you're not
here just for the boy.
You're here to intimidate
those witnesses.
And if the court
catches on to that,
believe me, it's all over.
Those men aren't
witnesses. They're paid liars.
Well, that's my problem.
Getting the truth
out of them is my job.
Now, it's... It's
a free society.
I can't tell you to stay or go.
But those men who are with you,
I'd get them out
of the courtroom
before they destroy everything
we've got going for us...
which isn't much right now.
I'm asking you...
to give me a shot at this.
Will you?
My name is Dick Silvers.
I live at 560 North Eaton.
And I work for the Black
and White Cab Company.
Were you in the vicinity of
15589 Peachtree Avenue
the night Congressman
McGinnis was murdered?
Yes, I was.
My dispatcher sent me
over to pick up a fare.
About what time did you arrive?
Do you recall?
Yes. That was around 8:25.
You certain?
Hey. I got my trip
sheet right here.
It shows the fare
got in my cab at 8:28.
She only kept me waiting
a couple of minutes.
While you were waiting,
how did you occupy your time?
The way I usually do.
I people watch.
So you were watching people
going in and out of
the office building.
But it was getting late.
Most people were
coming out of the building.
But I did see one person
going into the building.
Who was that
person? Do you know?
Yes.
That person sitting right
over there at the table.
You mean the
defendant, Craig Gentry.
That's right.
And you're certain that's the
man who entered the building
where Congressman
McGinnis has his offices
around 8:25 the night the
congressman was murdered?
Absolutely. No doubt in my mind.
Thank you, Mr. Silvers.
Nothing further.
No questions, Your Honor.
Ben? MATLOCK: Yeah?
Turkey.
Oh. Only thing they had left.
Oh, they were still open. Good.
Uh, no. I had to
bribe the counterman.
I gave him my phone number.
At least he thinks
it's my phone number.
Oh.
What's all this?
They're law books.
Oh, sometimes when I'm
stuck and can't do anything,
I open a lot of books,
and it makes me feel like...
Like you're doing something.
Doing something. Yeah.
I'll tell you the truth, and...
Unless we have a rabbit
pop up out of a
hat, and pretty quick,
Craig Gentry could be convicted.
I wish there were
something I could do to help.
Well, you have helped.
No, I haven't. Yes, you have.
You looked at all that tape.
You kept the office
running, went to law school,
and gave the counterman
your wrong number.
Otherwise, my stomach
would've kept me awake all night.
You know, Ben, maybe
you should go home.
This isn't really the kind of
case you should be working on
alone late at night
in a deserted building.
These people are
professional criminals.
Ben Matlock's office.
Uh, may I tell
him who's calling?
All right.
It's for you. Won't
say who it is.
I don't think you
should take it.
Thank you.
Hello?
Yeah.
Yeah, you don't say.
I'll be right there.
Be right where? Who was that?
That was that bartender.
He's decided he wants to talk.
Maybe he's our... Our rabbit.
Yeah. Okay.
Mr. Morrison?
Hey, Mickey.
www.tvsubtitles.net